<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Bretônio Sur La Github]]></title><description><![CDATA[Una Bitácora de Navegaciones]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 17:35:39 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bretonio.github.io/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Quefazeres]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://bretonio.github.io/images/firstlookingintohugo.png" alt="firstlookingintohugo.png">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Eu quero fazer o seguinte durantes as semanas que vêm.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Conseguir por fim o <code>git push origin master</code> ao site pessoal <a href="https://github.com/gringolalia">gringolalia</a>. Tenho dificuldades com Hugo.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Aprender <a href="https://middlemanapp.com/">middleman</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Installar Node.js e Python 3 nessa maldita máquina no rehab para poder trabalhar com Pelican e <a href="http://roots.cx">Roots</a> e outros durante o dia.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Conseguir dinheiro suficiente para botar meu wiki num <a href="http://sambodianas.nfshost.com/">servidor próprio</a>, accesível de qualquer lugar.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Criar um site para a organização <a href="https://sambodianasllc.github.io/">Sambodianas LLC</a>, com Jekyll, utilizando <a href="https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/13455621/jekyll-incorporated">jekyll incorporated</a>, como amostra, ou talvez <a href="https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/23162068/agency-jekyll-theme">Agency</a> ou outro tipo de site do qual a Neuza gostaria de montar&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;repositório de escritos da última década.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Criar um site de organização para Neuza, pode ser com Hexo.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Criar site de projeto com Jekyll e os temas <a href="https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/9884000/scribble">scribble</a> ou <a href="https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/9884000/scribble">flex</a>, ou talvez <a href="https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/16262460/redcup">redcup</a> ou qualquer outro com a simplicidade desejada.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>No Jekyll, entender o mecanismo <code>rake site:publish</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Montar o site pessoal [ColinBretonio] utilizando Pelican com o tema <a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes/tree/master/backdrop">backdrop</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Montar o site de projeto victor utilizando Hugo com o tema <a href="http://themes.gohugo.io/beautifulhugo/">Beautiful Hugo</a>, ajustando alguns dos variáveis para melhor a apresentação (control sobre o <code>&#8592;-more-&#8594;</code> e o  poder to ajustar o tamanho e alinhamento das imagens)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Começar um site em Hexo&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;talvez para nova organização&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;utilizando o tema <a href="https://github.com/ptsteadman/hexo-theme-corporate-example/blob/master/README.md">corporate</a>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Isso deve ser trabalho suficiente para afastar o mal gosto na boca causado pela queda e degolação brutal da rainha de Sambodia. Brasileiros, o quê é isso?</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/09/01/Quefazeres.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/09/01/Quefazeres.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[ github]]></category><category><![CDATA[ project pages]]></category><category><![CDATA[ organization]]></category><category><![CDATA[ quefazeres]]></category><category><![CDATA[ todos]]></category><category><![CDATA[ hexo]]></category><category><![CDATA[ pelican]]></category><category><![CDATA[ jekyll]]></category><category><![CDATA[ middleman]]></category><category><![CDATA[ roots.cx]]></category><category><![CDATA[ workflow]]></category><category><![CDATA[ ruby]]></category><category><![CDATA[ rake]]></category><category><![CDATA[ pelican]]></category><category><![CDATA[ python]]></category><category><![CDATA[ node.js]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[No Victory Over Hugo]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I lied the other day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am now able to push Web sites built with generators like <a href="https://neuza-paranhos.github.io/">Hexo</a> and Pelican to GitHub Pages, but not Hugo.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I cannot understand it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Building <a href="https://neuza-paranhos.github.io/2016/08/27/hello-world/">a Hexo site</a> in the local repo, for example. writes everything to the <code>public</code> directory and there is no <code>index.html</code> in the root. Unlike <a href="https://braytonio.github.io/">Jekyll</a> which writes it all to root. But eppur se muove.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is supposed to be the trick to doing the same with a Hugo site, but I cannot get it to work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://philippantar.com/posts/how-i-deploy-to-github-pages/">Some suggest</a> copying the contents of the <code>public</code> folder over to a separate folder, from which you will push.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Others suggest using two branches of the same repository, for source and for output. The logic of it, and those ASCII <a href="http://www.textualscholarship.org/stemmatics/">stemmatic diagrams</a>, make me dizzy.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://bretonio.github.io/images/githubhugoghostw450x.png" alt="The Ghostwriter WIth The Most Writers">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here is the thing: I have a really nice simplke blog, <a href="https://gringolalia.github.io/">My Paraguayan Progress Report</a>, above, with the <a href="http://themes.gohugo.io/ghostwriter/">ghostwriter</a> theme, which I want to use for charting my supposed technical progress instead of HubPress.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In any case I should not move forward without finally <a href="http://readwrite.com/2013/10/02/github-for-beginners-part-2/">educating myself</a> about <code>git</code> and all its mysteries. <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/configuring-a-publishing-source-for-github-pages/">This</a> is pretty basic, for example.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I guess I am the kind of guy who just jumps right in and does not read the freaking manual until he has developed ulcers googling solutions he does not really grok.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_brasilianas_of_the_day">Brasilianas of the Day</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here in Brazil, the Senate will start voting on the impeachment charges against President Dilma Rousseff. Ordinarily I would be very interested in following the media blitz surrounding the proceedings on  <a href="http://tupiwire.wordpress.com">The New World Lusophone Sousaphone</a>. I am after all a <a href="http://complit.berkeley.edu/">trained and licensed</a> Barthesian, though not McLuhanite, interpreter of mass culture.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Lately, however, this sort of thing just makes me nervous.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The coup will be consummated and there is nothing any can doup about it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://braytonio.github.io/2016-08-29-der-process/">What mainly impresses one</a> is how much the Glogo-dominated media has underplayed the story, with the exception of the final day of Rousseff&#8217;s testimony, covered closely by dozens of international news sources.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The story plays second fiddle today  to coverage of a shooting on a Rio beach involving a Polish tourist, as it played third bassoon the other day to the earthquake in Italy. <a href="https://books.google.com.br/books?id=yF2SG8BFDwkC&amp;pg=PA249&amp;lpg=PA249&amp;dq=umberto+eco+media+bias&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=Z1PBhiUW4L&amp;sig=Ct05RJzkaq9sxRK3XffNoumrjXk&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=0ahUKEwiDzYW99OvOAhUMjpAKHULeCqAQ6AEIMTAD#v=onepage&amp;q=umberto%20eco%20media%20bias&amp;f=false">Umberto Eco</a> (PDF) notes this as one of his ten categories of <a href="http://www.mediabias.it/">bias in the Italian media</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Sambodian subliminal message: «All is Quiet on the Political Front.»</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The interim government is large and in charge and almost certainly not going anywhere&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;Globo is already referring to the party of the president as the «opposition»&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;so go ahead, foreign investor and make your long-term plans. And yes, we plan to privatize like no tomorrow so get your checkbooks ready!</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_huck_finnegan_the_space_case">Huck Finnegan &amp; The Space Case</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I would normally be in rehab today but I am doing a Huck Finn number. Again.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today being our <strong>rodizio</strong>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;one day a week when you cannot drive from 9 to 5 on the Sambodian streets&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;and lacking funds on my <strong>*bilhete único</strong>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;a Sambodian Metro Pass&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;I resolve to sleep late and then hack GitHub Pages&#8201;&#8212;&#8201; I want to make a Pelican site with <a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes/tree/master/backdrop">backdrop</a>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201; until our Netflix hour.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For people of a certain age, we are really into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Get_Down">The Get Down</a>, which already has a Wikipedia page as extensive as that of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Get_Down">Ramon Llull</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But we are not really so old as that. I remember the mainstreaming of Grandmaster Flash and Kurtis Blow and to a lesser extent  <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planet_Rock:_The_Album">Afrika Baambataa</a> from freshman in college days, when me and all my friends worked all summer keeping <a href="http://kspc.org/">The Space</a> on the air.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>My DJ namme was Joey Dharma.</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/31/No-Victory-Over-Hugo.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/31/No-Victory-Over-Hugo.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bretonio Groks Project Pages]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://github.com/HubPress/hubpress.io/blob/master/Writers_Guide.adoc#hp-tags-for-metadata-tags">ASCIIDoc</a> just makes me angry and confused. I am sorry to say. This is partly why I intend to adapt one of my GitHub project pages for blogging my progress, if any, on my <a href="https://github.com/HubPress/hubpress.io/blob/master/Writers_Guide.adoc#hp-tags-for-metadata-tags">GitLab projects</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_bret_nio_decamps">Bretônio Decamps</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Yes, I guess I am abandoning Hubpress, so sorry. It taught me things, basic &amp; valuable things. Really. It is just that I am having success pushing project pages now and those can fill the bill for online notetaking needs, along with those project wikis.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Big. Britches</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Meantime I have set my wife up with <a href="https://neuza-paranhos.github.io/2016/08/27/hello-world/">a Web log that seems to please her</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Built it with Hexo. Uses a pretty standard <a href="https://startbootstrap.com/template-overviews/clean-blog/">Clean Blog</a> theme, but then I am not exactly the Le Corbusier of Web sites.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Now we just need a background image of our own. Perhaps a stock photo of an old-time <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linotype_machine">linotype machine</a>. I would like to tweak the taxonomy so as to create repositories of writings in the different genres Neuza works in: fiction, crónicas &#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Oh, and lest I forget: We need to translate the bugiganga into Portuguese as well.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_my_node_js_mess">My Node.js Mess</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>still having difficulties with Node.js and the <code>npm</code> installer in Arch Linux.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In some cases installation works and the command is available to in <code>/usr/bin/</code> or wherever.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In other cases, not so much. Much googling to little avail so far, though as I said I succeeded in installing, say, <a href="http://assemble.io/">Assemble</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_smelling_the_flores">Smelling the Flores</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Neuza tried  to interest me in a walk in the park just now, with the three meninas. Served me a mamão and a banana tapioca. No more coffee after 2:00 p.m. she says. My baby worries about me and my endless damned infernal computer noodling.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>She is right. I do not deserve her! But we have a  standing idiot box date at six every day. Watch Netflix while The News cooks the jantar.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Currently nearly to the end of <strong>Lost</strong> if you can believe our cultural backwardness. We hear the ending really sucks.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/27/Bretonio-Groks-Project-Pages.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/27/Bretonio-Groks-Project-Pages.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[ github]]></category><category><![CDATA[ project pages.]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Heckling Jekyll]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Braytonio/Braytonio.github.io/master/img/radio250.png" alt="Radio Daze">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I followed <a href="http://deanattali.com/beautiful-jekyll/">Dean&#8217;s instructions</a> to create a Beautiful Jekyll-themed site at <a href="https://braytonio.github.io/">Braytonio.github.io</a>, cloning it into my project <code>dir</code> and editing it and its config file with <a href="http://prose.io/#Braytonio">Prose.io</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>No joy.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I commit my changes after editing <code>aboutme.md</code> and filling out variables in <code>config.yml</code> but the page does not update with its new title, the «Irony Ant Bloc» (an anagram of my name).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I clone the repo to my machine to work on it here but now my jekyll installation makes fubar noises.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I mess with that for a while and then manage to start building with <code>bundle exec jekyll build</code>. But this yields</p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>control characters are not allowed at line 1, column 1</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Urgh!</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_urgh_a_music_war">Urgh! (A Music War)</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I say again: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Urgh!_A_Music_War">Urgh!</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(I actually attended that groundbreaking musical  event.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I even had my picture on the cover of Surfer magazine as a member of the Dead Boys mosh pit.)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And then I get the e-mail notice of build failure.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_welcome_advice_is_advice_that_works">Welcome Advice Is Advice That Works</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But hooray! There is <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/page-build-failed-config-file-error/">advice</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can either check line by line or simple go back to the original <code>_conf.yml</code> and re-enter my settings more carefully. I think maybe resetting the <code>baseurl</code> to `"/" was the problem.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And perhaps the problem is not with the Jekyll installation after all.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And so off and so forth.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_neuzinha_muse_of_the_digital_arts">Neuzinha, Muse of the Digital Arts</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Neuza is actually excited at the prospect of me <a href="https://github.com/neuza-paranhos/neuza-paranhos.github.io">building her a groovy Web site</a> where she can publish all her fabulous writings.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>She sometimes refers to herself as «computer widow» because I spend so much time hacking away at digital windmills, so it is nice to have the vote of confidence.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So I was surprised yesterday when she said she knew what Github was.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I guess I should not have been: she and Sergio Crusco have been working for a client in the Google Brasil family of fantastically advanced little ventures.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Em fim: I think I will <a href="https://www.notionsandnotes.org/tech/web-development/pelican-static-blog-setup.html">try out Pelican</a> for this modest domestic project. And now to walk the cadelas.</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bretonio/bretonio.github.io/master/images/hexomynewtoys.png" alt="hexomynewtoys.png">
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/24/Heckling-Jekyll.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/24/Heckling-Jekyll.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Waging War on Windows]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I hate this machine, an antiquated Windows 7 box in the computer lab at the Cancer Ward. (I have AMPPS installed as a localhost server for testing CMS but it is pretty damn <code>fubar</code>.)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For one thing, the permissions will not let me install Python or Node.js, although they are fine with Ruby.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tech support? There are rumors that it atually exists, but no sign of intelligent life yet.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So I cannot work in my down time here.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Windows command line interface is also a pain in the ass.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>No <code>unzip</code> command, and the <code>edit</code> command gives you an editor which does not follow your keymap&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;no freaking double quotes, which one needs for front matter and any number of things.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So it looks like I will be stuck working with <a href="https://www.ruby-toolbox.com/categories/static_website_generation">Ruby sitegens</a> during the week: Jekyll &amp; <a href="http://nanoc.ws/doc/tutorial/">Nanoc</a> &amp; <a href="https://middlemanapp.com/">Middleman</a> &amp; <a href="https://www.ruby-toolbox.com/projects/awestruct">Awestruct</a> &#8230;&#8203; should be fun.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/22/Waging-War-on-Windows.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/22/Waging-War-on-Windows.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chove Chuva]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>You know what might be perfect for the projects I am planning?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://blog.kdheepak.com/how-to-set-up-a-pelican-blog-with-github-pages.html">Pelican</a> with a theme called <a href="https://github.com/yuex/pelican-chameleon">Chameleon</a> which is translatable into various [Bootstrap]-based themes, like <a href="https://bootswatch.com/united/">United</a>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;an homage to Ubuntu&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;or <a href="https://bootswatch.com/cosmo/">Cosmos</a>. Cosmos I really like.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://blog.kdheepak.com/how-to-set-up-a-pelican-blog-with-github-pages.html">Pelican Bootstrap3</a> has the same flexibility.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But I do not understand how to reset the variables in these themes as instructed.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>It appears you have to replace THEME = in <strong>pelicanconf.py</strong> with BOOTSTRAP_THEME = &#8230;&#8203; Or do you?</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>No, I see now, you first refer to THEME = 'pelican-bootstrap3' and then add the other line below it.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And it works!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This may not seem like much of a technical triumph to you but I majored in poetry, as I often say. (I practically have a piled higher and deeper in advanced literary thinkology).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am down to <a href="http://themes.gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> and <a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/install.html">Pelican</a> and <a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/content.html">Jekyll</a> for my site-builder of choice. Jekyll is kind of hard to use.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://getnikola.com/getting-started.html">Nikola</a>, maintained in the AUR repository, is also interesting&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;<code>yaourt python-nikola-git</code></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But it uses reStructuredText, of which am not at all fond. Start talking about recompiling and my eyes glaze over.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Are there other such tools in AUR? Jekyll for one is. Ruby Toolbox has a whole section on them.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The time comes when you have to choose and get on with things.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to know the truth, I am probably going to use a simple CMS for these projects because the authors will want the satisfaction of learning to manage their <strong>conteúdo</strong> themselves.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>(It is a learning exercise for patients of the Cancer Ward.)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But Mrs. Me is calling. Time for a late lunch of arroz, feijão e salada, and «Brasileirinho» playing on Radio USP.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/21/Chove-Chuva.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/21/Chove-Chuva.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[ open source]]></category><category><![CDATA[ CMS]]></category><category><![CDATA[ static site generator]]></category><category><![CDATA[ css]]></category><category><![CDATA[ themes]]></category><category><![CDATA[ theming]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Bootstrap]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Quinta-feira Installathon Blues]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bretonio/bretonio.github.io/master/images/hexomynewtoys.png" alt="hexomynewtoys.png">
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have been obsessively trying out <a href="https://www.staticgen.com/">static site generators</a> of all different sorts.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>They include <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-and-use-hugo-a-static-site-generator-on-ubuntu-14-04">Hugo</a>, <a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes">Pelican</a>, <a href="http://www.andismith.com/blog/2014/02/getting-started-with-assemble/">Assemble</a>, <a href="https://middlemanapp.com/">Middleman</a>, <a href="https://middlemanapp.com/">Hexo</a>, &amp; naturally <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Of these, to make a long story short, Hugo and Pelican seem easiest to work with for a poetry major like myself.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An obstacle in my quest for encyclopedic testing of these systems: I cannot get the Node.js package manager to work properly. This means I am unable to check out, for example, <a href="https://github.com/gatsbyjs/gatsby">Gatsby</a> for the time being. Or [Sculpin] or [Assemble] or <a href="http://www.metalsmith.io/">Metalsmith</a> or <a href="https://harpjs.com/docs/quick-start">Harp</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Googling for a solution. Cactus and other Python packages are accessible.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In the meantime I added quickstart crib sheets on Pelican and Hugo to my DokuWiki.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_stop_in_the_name_of_fernando_pessoa">Stop in the Name of Fernando Pessoa</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I should stop now and return to poetry major tasks such as blogging Brazilian &amp; Sambodian&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;São Paulo&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;politics and culture and writing my modest little mediahttp://bootswatch.com/flatly/ studies column in Portuguese.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I should also select a package and begin working on two sites I am pledged to develop for the Cancer Ward and its denizens. I actually think that <a href="http://urubu-quickstart.jandecaluwe.com/start.html">Urubu</a> would work very nicely with the <a href="http://bootswatch.com/flatly/#buttons">Flatly theme</a>, the same used by Typesetter, which however lacks a decent blogging module.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_sharpening_the_pencil">Sharpening the Pencil</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Messing obsessively with the tech is like sharpening your pencil compulsively until you have no time to write because you have to go to the stationery store. Again. Formulating the To-Do list on my wiki becomes an end in itself. Writing projects are endlessly deferred until the wiki becomes an exercise i the possibility of writing and not writing in itself. In the same vein as Jorge Luis Borges, I guess.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But still, I love the tech with a passion and refuse to let my chronic newbism get in the way of hacking the CMS or sitegen.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect1">
<h2 id="_verborrhea_typophilia">Verborrhea &amp; Typophilia</h2>
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have always loved the tech of publishing, from the ancient linotype machine at the South Pasadena Review to the ancient Quark XPress server at Internet World, where I first learned Web publishing on a Cold Fusion system.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In junior high school print shop, we made fliers and business cards the same way Gutenberg made Bibles.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In graduate school at Berkeley I did a fantastic paleography seminar with Prof. Joseph Duggan. I did a project on a medieval Iberian author who tried to institute quality control against the constant slips of the pen of half-blind monks&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;hence <a href="http://www.textualscholarship.org/stemmatics/">Lachmann&#8217;s method</a>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;by maintaining true copies of his works at various locations and mentioning them in the preface to his work.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Copying books by hand was an exercise in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_whispers">Chinese Whispers</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was so inspired by this course that I considered dropping my doctorate and doing a master&#8217;s in library science&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;a very advanced and challenging field when practiced correctly.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In any event, I love typography and layout and writing heds and subheds and jump heds. What I would not give to be back on the New York editorial scene working for Jane or GQ or Artforum as in the rapidly receding past.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Essay idea in honor of Umberto Eco: The Web designer as neo-Medieval scribe.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/19/My-Quinta-feira-Installathon-Blues.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/19/My-Quinta-feira-Installathon-Blues.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Double-Blogging on the Triple Frontier]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>My friends think I am crazy, triple-blogging to GitHub, <a href="https://tupiwire.wordpress.com/2016/08/19/above-the-hubbub/">Wordpress</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/ColinBrayton/status/766684201324253185">Twitter</a> &amp; <a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100007406176198&amp;fref=nf&amp;pnref=story">Facebook</a> all at once.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I remind you: Blogging does not pay my bills and so you get what you pay for.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That goes for the invitation from the powers that be at the Cancer Ward to write a pamphlet on mandalas and art therapy and the requests to translate scientific journal articles.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>What were the words Chuck Berry used to say before every concert? «Pay me my money». I need my dollars, my shekels, my quid, my reais &#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/19/Double-Blogging-on-the-Triple-Frontier.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/19/Double-Blogging-on-the-Triple-Frontier.html</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Hubbub]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://ampps">AMPPS</a> did not work out well for me on Linux Mint.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In order to alter the PHP configuration&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;php.ini&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;for a needy application, I had to stop the MongoDB server.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But it would not stop.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I suspect I would have had to uninstall a redundant installation of MongoDB&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;I did not know I had it on my system&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;before installing the AMPPS package.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Some other time.</p>
</div>
<div style="page-break-after: always;"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_wix_vix">Wix: Vix!</h5>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I promised a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beco_do_Batman">Sambodian</a> psychoanalyst acquaintance of mine I would <strong>dar um jeito</strong> with his <a href="http://www.luizfernandofontesteixeira.com.br">Web site</a>￼.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="http://whatcms.org/?s=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.luizfernandofontesteixeira.com.br&amp;na=&amp;nb=bf0d6b0cd6&amp;nc=a283d9370b39da2dc4bac2aabadcb296">What CMS</a> says he is likely using <a href="https://www.wix.com/support/html5/article/request-cms-system">Wix</a> for his current site.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>«Stunning». Everything is «stunning» with those Wix people.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>«Your stunning blog».</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Set all Web design phasers on «stun».</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The thing is that Doctor Jungfraud writes and posts a lot of dated articles for newspapers and journals but he is not technically inclined. His Wix site basically works but is ugly as sin.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>He says he wants to learn a bit more about managing his own content but finds those Big 5 CMS software packages hard to use. Something like Grav might be useful. You can date your content at will, for example.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And who does not?
<a href="http://tiki.org/tiki-index.php">TikiWiki</a> drives me crazy for example. But there are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_content_management_systems">so many choices</a></p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Unfortunately, the sort of drag and drop layout manager and WYSIWYG text editor offered by an in many ways admirable project like <a href="http://sambodianas.typesetter.com">Typesetter</a> is not really going to be that much easier for Zé Psychology Major. As <a href="https://learn.getgrav.org/content/markdown">they say</a></p>
</div>
<div class="quoteblock">
<blockquote>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Let&#8217;s face it: Writing content for the Web is tiresome. WYSIWYG editors help alleviate this task, but they generally result in horrible code, or worse yet, ugly web pages.</p>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Typesetter is sort of the Quark Express of CMS. And Quark is the 1958 Chevy Impala of offline words into typography-on-paper machines.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>So maybe Doctor Strangelove will just have to hire me&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;dirt cheap&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;to manage his <strong>conteúdo</strong> for him.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect4">
<h5 id="_dimanche_apr_s_midi">Dimanche Après-Midi</h5>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This Sunday afternoon I am focusing on <a href="https://learn.getgrav.org/themes/theme-tutorial">Grav</a> and <a href="http://www.typesettercms.com/Docs">Typesetter</a> for purposes of <a href="http://sambodianas.nfshost.com/cbrayton">my own eventual Web presence</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am getting the hang of <a href="http://asciidoctor.org/docs/asciidoc-syntax-quick-reference/">AsciiDoctor</a> now, thank you very much.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>All of this is probably a grand waste of what little time I have left on this earth, but between walking the dogs, picking up din-din at the Natureba da Terra, and catching up on <strong>Lost</strong>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;a decade late, what am I, Robinson Crusoe?&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;I am not really doing much else.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deleuze_and_Guattari">Deleuze &amp; Guattari</a> to read&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;is their notion of «desiring machines» really the inspiration for <strong>The Matrix?</strong>&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alu%C3%ADsio_Azevedo">Aluísio Azevedo</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>But <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macuna%C3%ADma_(novel)">ai, que preguiça</a></strong> &#8230;&#8203;</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://bretonio.github.io/images/200px-Cathar_cross.svg.png" alt="The Cathar Cross: Dualism in Extremis">
</div>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/13/The-Hubbub.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/13/The-Hubbub.html</guid><category><![CDATA[AMPPS]]></category><category><![CDATA[ LAMPP stack]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Apache]]></category><category><![CDATA[ CMS]]></category><category><![CDATA[ hosting]]></category><category><![CDATA[ development]]></category><category><![CDATA[ server]]></category><category><![CDATA[ WYSIWYG]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Wix]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Grav]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Typesetter]]></category><category><![CDATA[ typography]]></category><category><![CDATA[ layout]]></category><category><![CDATA[ publishing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Quark]]></category><category><![CDATA[ psychoanalysis]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HubPress: A First Posting]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Oh, I see.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The save icon does not appear unless you have a first-level heading as your title.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Okay.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I am an aging poetry major who&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;having worked in technical writing and other fields over the course of a long &amp; eclectic career&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;has developed an insatiable curiosity about all aspects of Web publishing&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;the many tools of this bitch goddess of a trade.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://www.questia.com/library/745252/words-into-type-a-guide-in-the-preparation-of-manuscripts">Words Into Type</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An <a href="https://www.archlinux.org/">Arch Linux</a> man myself, I recently installed <a href="https://www.ampps.com">AMPPS</a> on the crappy Windows XP box at my place of internment and am reveling in the opportunity to auto-install&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;count them&#8201;&#8212;&#8201;401 flavors of what in post-modernity we cannot help  calling content management.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Content is what comes in McDonalds apple pies. Humans produce communication. But oh well.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I have a separate <a href="http://linuxmint.com">Linux Mint</a> box to which I think I will try installing the AMPPS package after I back up my http folder to the Cloud.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Eventually, what I want to do myself is figure out how to compile my <a href="http://dokuwiki.org">DocuWiki</a> book of hours and my <a href="http://datenstrom.se/yellow/">Yellow CMS</a> installation into <a href="https://www.staticgen.com/">static HTML that can also be pushed to GitHub</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>One of these days I will figure it all out. In the meantime, many mercis beaucoups to Anthonny for this groovy innovation.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/11/Hub-Press-A-First-Posting.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bretonio.github.io/2016/08/11/Hub-Press-A-First-Posting.html</guid><category><![CDATA[HubPress]]></category><category><![CDATA[ blog]]></category><category><![CDATA[ open source]]></category><category><![CDATA[ GitHub]]></category><category><![CDATA[ content management]]></category><category><![CDATA[ CMS]]></category><category><![CDATA[ publishing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ writing]]></category><category><![CDATA[ poetry]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brayton]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>